ALCHEMY OF SOULS PART 2
&lrm;還魂 &lrm;第二部
Throughout my life,
&lrm;我在這棵樹上
I spent most of my time on this tree alone.
&lrm;獨自度過的時間分明更加漫長
So I wonder what it was
&lrm;為何
that made me wait for someone to come for me.
&lrm;還會心生期待等著某人來接我呢？
Because we made a promise.
&lrm;因為我們約定好了
You may not have remembered me,
&lrm;即便妳不記得我
but you remembered our promise to be together,
&lrm;妳仍記得我們許諾要廝守的約定
which is why you waited for me.
&lrm;所以妳才在等我
I asked you to carry me last time, but you just left.
&lrm;之前我要你抱著我走 &lrm;你卻直接丟下我對吧？
There.
&lrm;好
Are you happy?
&lrm;這樣滿意了吧？
If this is a brief chance to keep the promise we made,
&lrm;若能暫時給我們機會履行約定
let us spend time together like any other couple
&lrm;就讓我們像其他平凡的戀人般
who have met after pining and longing for each other.
&lrm;因為思念而見面
These chestnuts have already matured.
&lrm;野栗已經成熟了呢
-You are right. -Shall we cook them in rice?
&lrm;-真的耶 &lrm;-要煮飯來吃嗎？
Sure.
&lrm;好啊
Do you remember throwing things at me when I was cooking last time?
&lrm;妳還記得我以前煮飯時 &lrm;妳亂丟東西嗎？
-I did? -"I did"?
&lrm;-我有嗎？ &lrm;-“我有嗎？”
You even threw a knife at me.
&lrm;妳還朝著我扔刀子
-Like this? -Do not do it.
&lrm;-像這樣嗎？ &lrm;-別這樣
I bet I threw it like this.
&lrm;我應該是這樣扔的
All right.
&lrm;是啊
I will pretend as if this is nothing more
&lrm;就宛如平凡的某一天般
than just another ordinary day together
&lrm;沒有什麼好惋惜或遺憾的
and I will watch over you until the end.
&lrm;我會那樣守護妳直到最後
We should make chestnut rice
&lrm;久違地來煮個栗子飯吧
since both you and Master Lee like it.
&lrm;你和李先生都很喜歡嘛
Master Lee?
&lrm;李先生？
He is currently at his hut in Danhyanggok.
&lrm;他現在在斷響谷的住所裡
He was the one who brought me here.
&lrm;是他把我帶來這的
Did the Unanimous Assembly ask you to take the ice stone out of Jang Uk?
&lrm;萬長會是否要求妳取出張煜的冰石？
I told them I could not
&lrm;我已經婉拒他們了
because there is another soul shifter he has yet to catch.
&lrm;因為仍有還魂人等著他去追捕
I see you have decided to let him catch you.
&lrm;看來妳已決定要落入張煜手中了
Then you should go to Danhyanggok.
&lrm;那就去斷響谷吧
I am also responsible for how things turned out for you two,
&lrm;你們倆會走到今天這一步 &lrm;我也有責任
and I cannot sit back and do nothing like I did before.
&lrm;我不能再像以往一樣坐視不管了
It is time
&lrm;我也得
that I do my part.
&lrm;盡自己的本分才行
What is it that you have to do with us?
&lrm;你怎麼會找我們過來？
I did nothing when you were a young master and a servant.
&lrm;以前你們以主僕關係相待時 &lrm;我都沒插手
I also did not interfere when you were a master and a pupil.
&lrm;得知你們以師徒相稱，也佯裝不知
However,
&lrm;然而
I cannot sit by and watch as one must be hunted
&lrm;現在你們成了追捕的關係
and the other must be the hunter.
&lrm;我就不能再置之不理了
So I wish to put an end to your current relationship.
&lrm;我希望能將你們的關係畫下句點
You saved my life, so I will accept whatever choice you make.
&lrm;你是我的救命恩人
Then will you follow my decision no matter what?
&lrm;那不管我吩咐妳做什麼 &lrm;妳都會聽從嗎？
Then I want you two…
&lrm;那麼你們倆…
to have a wedding.
&lrm;舉行婚禮吧
I shall be your witness.
&lrm;我會為你們見證
I want you two to be officially married.
&lrm;你們正式結為夫妻吧
Let us get ready.
&lrm;趕緊做好準備吧
The weather is nice, so let us get it done and over with.
&lrm;天氣和煦宜人，我們就速戰速決吧
All right.
&lrm;好的
Listen, you two.
&lrm;你們倆
Is this a matriculation ceremony?
&lrm;是在參加拜師儀式嗎？
Oh, do you wish to be my pupil?
&lrm;原來你們想成為我的徒弟啊
Will you drink chaste herb tea
&lrm;那要從今日開始飲用斷根茶
and practice chastity starting today?
&lrm;斷絕色欲，讓六根清淨嗎？
-No. -No way.
&lrm;-不要 &lrm;-我不想
This is a wedding.
&lrm;既然是婚禮
You should be facing each other.
&lrm;就該相視而坐啊
Oh, right.
&lrm;喔，對耶
A wedding ceremony is how you announce your marriage
&lrm;婚禮雖是將夫妻關係
to the people around you.
&lrm;告知周圍之人的一種儀式
But it is also to inform the skies.
&lrm;但同時也是向天稟告的儀式
"We have decided to be together."
&lrm;“我們決定要廝守了
"Therefore, no one can set us apart."
&lrm;所以誰都不能恣意拆散我們”
That is what the message is.
&lrm;如此向天稟告
Now, Jang Uk of the Jang family and…
&lrm;那麼張氏家族的張煜…
Come to think of it,
&lrm;仔細一想
you have four names.
&lrm;妳有四個名字呢
You were born as Cho Yeong, but you grew up as the assassin, Naksu.
&lrm;出生時名為趙縈
Then you lived as Mu-deok,
&lrm;爾後又成為無德
and now you are Jin Bu-yeon.
&lrm;現在則是陳復妍
I never had a chance to live
&lrm;我不曾單用一個名字
with just one name.
&lrm;好好地生活過
Which name shall I call you by?
&lrm;要用哪個名字稱呼妳？
The name that my parents gave me when I was born.
&lrm;就用我出世時父母為我取的名字…
I would like to be called Cho Yeong.
&lrm;趙縈吧
Uk and Yeong.
&lrm;煜與縈
Your name means "light."
&lrm;你的名字蘊有光之意
And your name means "shadow."
&lrm;妳的名字則代表著影子
Light and shadow.
&lrm;光與影
It may be that you two
&lrm;也許你們
were fated to meet from the start.
&lrm;打從一開始就是命中註定
Let us now begin the wedding ceremony of Jang Uk and Cho Yeong.
&lrm;那麼
It is a wedding drink.
&lrm;這是合歡酒
If you drink that,
&lrm;喝下那杯之後
it means we are officially married.
&lrm;我們就正式結為夫妻了
Go on. Drink up.
&lrm;將它一飲而盡
If you turn this off, I will take you with me.
&lrm;若妳能將它熄滅，我就帶妳走
You and I…
&lrm;我們從很久以前…
have liked each other for a long time.
&lrm;就喜歡彼此了
I shall always stay by your side at this distance.
&lrm;日後我都會以此等距離陪在你身邊
That is my promise.
&lrm;這是我的承諾
I must be going crazy…
&lrm;看來…
because of you.
&lrm;我真的被妳搞瘋了
I found another use for you.
&lrm;妳有這種用處應該也不錯
After all, you are offering to substitute for her.
&lrm;反正妳都願意在現實中當她的替身了
But this is my hand that you are holding,
&lrm;總之你現在牽的是我的手
and it will be me who holds you and puts you to bed at night.
&lrm;要抱住你或哄你入睡的手
So when you are looking at me, see me for who I am.
&lrm;所以當你這樣看向我時 &lrm;就聚精會神，好好看清楚
You look pretty.
&lrm;很美
You told me to see you for who you were.
&lrm;妳不是要我別崩潰，好好看著妳嗎？
That is what I am trying to do.
&lrm;所以我想聚精會神徹底看個清楚
I will also…
&lrm;那我…
boast to everyone that you lit up a dark path for me late at night.
&lrm;也要跟他們炫耀
Sure, go ahead.
&lrm;好啊，就這樣跟他們說吧
I plan to find my own room.
&lrm;我會找到屬於我的房間
I will find out who I really am and decorate my room with my own traits.
&lrm;我會好好想清楚自己是誰 &lrm;布置好我的房間
I hope…
&lrm;到時候
that makes it easier for you to find me.
&lrm;希望你能順利找到我
I will keep you warm and help you rest comfortably.
&lrm;我會給你溫暖，讓你能安心休憩
I just pine for you.
&lrm;就只是很想妳
That is why I came to see you.
&lrm;非見到妳不可，因此我才會來
I liked you from the start.
&lrm;我一開始就喜歡上你了
I knew the moment I saw you.
&lrm;我第一眼就認出來了
You are my husband.
&lrm;我的夫婿
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
&lrm;現在你們已是夫妻
You have informed the skies through this ceremony,
&lrm;不但舉行了婚禮，也已向天稟告
so I wish you a long life together.
&lrm;希望你們能長相廝守
Among all the married couples I have seen through my entire life,
&lrm;在我歷經了漫長歲月 &lrm;見過的所有夫妻中
you two are the dearest.
&lrm;你們是最天造地設的一對
I promised you
&lrm;我答應過妳
that I would bring you up here.
&lrm;要帶妳登上這裡吧
You were right. You can see the world from up here.
&lrm;就如妳所說，一切都盡收眼底呢
It is nice.
&lrm;真棒
Now that I look at you like this,
&lrm;這樣看著你
it feels as if it has been a long time since we last met,
&lrm;感覺像是許久沒見了
but it also feels as if we met yesterday.
&lrm;又像昨日才見過般
It feels strange.
&lrm;心情有點微妙
It feels like I held your hand a long time ago.
&lrm;這雙手感覺像是我許久前就牽著
But it also feels like I only recently held it for the very first time.
&lrm;又像是不久前才第一次牽住般
Everything is clear to me now.
&lrm;一切對我來說都很清晰鮮明
Deep down inside,
&lrm;因為我一直
I recognized you from the start.
&lrm;都有好好地看著妳
Just like when we first met.
&lrm;就像第一眼就認出妳般
I recognized the girl with the blue marks in her eyes.
&lrm;我認出了眼中映著藍色光芒的…
I recognized you.
&lrm;妳
Do you think Bu-yeon is with Jang Uk right now?
&lrm;姐姐現在
Jang Uk will have gone to find her
&lrm;她那樣離開了萬長會
because of what she said at the Unanimous Assembly.
&lrm;張煜應該會去找她
Why did you not stop her?
&lrm;妳為何沒阻止她？
Jang Uk got rid of Jin Mu,
&lrm;張煜除掉了陳武
and Bu-yeon found the Jinyowon Plaque.
&lrm;而她找到了傍牌
Regardless of anything,
&lrm;無論如何
the truth is that they both protected Jinyowon.
&lrm;他們倆都守住了辰曜院
I would like to think that she is looking out for the two of them.
&lrm;希望那位能關照他們兩人
"She"?
&lrm;那位？
I asked them how they first met each other here.
&lrm;我問過他們起初是如何在此相遇的
They said someone had opened the door to this place.
&lrm;他們說是有人把門開著 &lrm;兩人才會碰面
Do you really believe
&lrm;你當真相信那位的靈魂
that her soul remained in Jinyowon along with the ice stone
&lrm;與冰石一同留在辰曜院內
and was reborn as my daughter?
&lrm;爾後作為我女兒出世嗎？
How is that even possible?
&lrm;那種事怎麼可能會發生？
My existence is proof that it is possible.
&lrm;那種事是有可能的 &lrm;我不就是活生生的鐵證嗎？
I am alive because I entered the dead body of a young boy.
&lrm;我進到已死的孩子體內活了過來
She may have done the same.
&lrm;那位想必也能用同樣的方式重生
Let us say you are right and that it is possible.
&lrm;就當那種事如你所言 &lrm;確實有可能會發生吧
What could be the reason that she chose to stay?
&lrm;那究竟是為了什麼
I am sure there is a good reason
&lrm;分明有什麼理由
why she chose to stay with the ice stone instead of leaving 200 years ago.
&lrm;讓她在200年前沒有離開
It sounds like you know what that reason may be.
&lrm;看來你心中已經有底了
She must have protected the ice stone because it was going to be used one day.
&lrm;既然她守護了冰石
Jin Seol-ran and my master, Seo Gyeong, went through the Great Chaos,
&lrm;陳雪蘭
and I fear that the same kind of chaos may occur once again.
&lrm;天下大亂時期
The fire bird is safe.
&lrm;火鳥安然無恙
Jin Mu is dead.
&lrm;而陳武已喪命
Heo Yeom stocked this place with food and firewood
&lrm;許琰已預先打理好，讓我來時能棲身
knowing I would come back here one day.
&lrm;他不但備好糧食，連柴火都補滿了
It will be enough to last you a month.
&lrm;應該足以讓你們在此過上一個月
A month?
&lrm;一個月嗎？
What is the matter? Is it too short?
&lrm;怎麼？太短了嗎？
I did not come hoping to spend a lifetime together.
&lrm;我來此不是期望能久居
I just came to stay by her side until the very last moment.
&lrm;而是抱著要守護她到最後的覺悟前來
That could last a month, two weeks,
&lrm;雖然不曉得那會是一個月、半個月
or even just a few days.
&lrm;或者僅有幾日
But I decided not to keep count.
&lrm;但我已決定不去細數
I am going to believe
&lrm;我相信我們會迎來明日
that we will always have tomorrow.
&lrm;並以這種心態度過每一天
How many of Naksu's memories have returned?
&lrm;落壽的記憶恢復了多少？
There is still
&lrm;她還有些記憶
a memory she does not recall.
&lrm;尚未恢復
You said you were dying to know
&lrm;你說過想知道
how I felt at that last moment with you.
&lrm;我和你共度的最後一刻 &lrm;是何種心情吧？
That moment will probably be
&lrm;或許那一刻的記憶
the very last memory that comes back to me.
&lrm;會是我最後找回的一段記憶
When I recall that last memory…
&lrm;等我想起最後的記憶
I will give you a sign like this.
&lrm;我會這樣給你信號
Then I will tell you what I remember.
&lrm;然後我會把那時的記憶傳達給你
It will be…
&lrm;那將是我給你的…
my last love letter to you.
&lrm;最後一封情書
In the past, I could not understand
&lrm;我以前還無法理解
why Master Seo Gyeong kept his love letter unsent
&lrm;為何徐經大師寫了情書
despite having written it.
&lrm;卻不交給對方
But now I understand why he would have been unable to send that letter.
&lrm;無論如何都無法傳達出去的感受為何
That love letter was for Jin Seol-ran.
&lrm;那封情書應該是寫給陳雪蘭的
I hope the love you have for each other will somehow reach her as well.
&lrm;希望你們之間的情書
Heo Yeom also got me new bedding.
&lrm;許琰應該也為我添置了新的寢具
Maybe it is in storage.
&lrm;是放在倉房裡嗎？
Jin Seol-ran?
&lrm;陳雪蘭？
What is this barrier? Did you create it?
&lrm;這是什麼結界？是妳布下的嗎？
That is the fire bird.
&lrm;是火鳥
The fire bird will dry out the world.
&lrm;火鳥將會讓大地乾涸
I hoped that something so tragic would never happen.
&lrm;我一直希望這種悲劇不要發生
But the foolish greed of humans will lead the world to burn to ashes.
&lrm;但是人類愚蠢的貪欲 &lrm;最終將讓整個世界化為灰燼
The fire bird
&lrm;火鳥
is going to escape?
&lrm;問世了？
I just showed you
&lrm;方才讓你目睹的景象
what is going to happen to this world.
&lrm;是往後這塊土地將會發生的事
I foresaw this happening a very long time ago.
&lrm;我在許久之前就預見了此事
You are able to see the future?
&lrm;妳能預見日後發生的事？
Who are you?
&lrm;妳是何人？
A priestess?
&lrm;神女嗎？
You used the yin-and-yang jade to summon me, right?
&lrm;就是妳用陰陽玉召喚我過來的吧？
I could not leave, for I was scared that the world would fall into ruin.
&lrm;我怕世界會再度毀滅才留了下來
But I only ended up contributing to the summoning of the fire bird
&lrm;沒想到反而召喚出火鳥，火上添油
and making this world burn.
&lrm;讓整個世界陷入火海
I am not capable of stopping what will happen.
&lrm;我無法阻止此事發生
It can only be stopped by the man
&lrm;唯有不得存在
who was born against the laws of nature under the King's Star.
&lrm;卻活下來的帝王星才能阻止
I have been hiding under the shadow that was created by your light.
&lrm;我一直躲在你的光所映照出的影子裡
Now I plan to cast that shadow aside and step out into the world.
&lrm;現在我打算拋開影子，邁向世界了
Cast the shadow aside
&lrm;妳要拋開影子
and step out into the world?
&lrm;邁向世界？
Does that mean
&lrm;那麼
you are Jin Bu-yeon?
&lrm;妳是陳復妍嗎？
That is right.
&lrm;沒錯
That is the name I was given when I was reborn.
&lrm;那是我重生後獲得的名字
Jin Bu-yeon attracted your shadow,
&lrm;陳復妍牽引著你的影子
used it,
&lrm;予以利用後
and will make it disappear.
&lrm;打算讓其消失
The world I foresaw will come no matter what.
&lrm;我預見的世界定會來臨
And when it does,
&lrm;那麼一來
tragic events will occur.
&lrm;將會發生淒慘萬分的悲劇
Just as Jin Seol-ran helped Seo Gyeong stop the Great Chaos a long time ago,
&lrm;就像許久之前
you are the only person who can stop the fire bird,
&lrm;能阻止火鳥的也只有你一人
and Jin Bu-yeon must come into this world to help you achieve that.
&lrm;陳復妍必須出世
Jin Bu-yeon attracted your shadow,
&lrm;陳復妍牽引著你的影子
used it,
&lrm;予以利用後
and will make it disappear.
&lrm;打算讓其消失
Did you meet…
&lrm;你見到…
Jin Bu-yeon?
&lrm;陳復妍了嗎？
Yes.
&lrm;嗯
I ended up seeing something
&lrm;我還看到了未來…
that is inevitable.
&lrm;必將發生的事
According to Jin Mu's plan,
&lrm;按照陳武的計策
we must first take the fire bird out of Jinyowon.
&lrm;我們必須先取出辰曜院裡的火鳥
Then we must confiscate the Jinyowon Plaque
&lrm;那就勢必得再次召開萬長會
by gathering another Unanimous Assembly.
&lrm;先將辰曜院的傍牌收回
We need to keep Songrim out of it,
&lrm;我們還得將松林排除在外
but how will we justify it?
&lrm;可有何由頭？
We must use Jang Uk as our justification.
&lrm;自然要拿張煜當藉口了
He disobeyed the King's command, did he not?
&lrm;畢竟他抗旨不遵啊
That is right.
&lrm;沒錯
When should we gather the Unanimous Assembly?
&lrm;那我們應該何時召開萬長會呢？
Are you all right?
&lrm;你沒事吧？
Forget about the Unanimous Assembly and the Jinyowon Plaque.
&lrm;別管什麼萬長會跟傍牌了
We have no time to waste.
&lrm;我已經不能再等了
We must go to Jinyowon at once and bring out the fire bird.
&lrm;我們立刻到辰曜院取出火鳥吧
We must do it now!
&lrm;即刻動身！
Why did His Majesty gather the mages of the Unanimous Assembly at this hour?
&lrm;殿下為何這麼晚 &lrm;還在大殿召集萬長會眾術士？
I do not know why,
&lrm;小的不知緣由
but I think one of the mages is a soul shifter.
&lrm;但其中一位術士似乎是還魂人
He absorbed the energy of one of the eunuchs.
&lrm;聽聞一名內官被他吸取了水氣
A soul shifter is in the palace?
&lrm;大殿有還魂人
Then His Majesty is in danger.
&lrm;殿下豈不是有危險？
-We must stop him. -It is hard to believe,
&lrm;-必須前去阻止 &lrm;-此事小的也不敢相信
but I think that soul shifter
&lrm;但那名還魂人
is someone you know, Your Royal Highness.
&lrm;您似乎也認識
Someone I know?
&lrm;我認識？
Who?
&lrm;誰？
It is me, Your Royal Highness.
&lrm;邸下，是我
You are the Queen's relative from Seoho Fortress, are you not?
&lrm;你不是王妃娘娘 &lrm;從西湖城來的親戚嗎？
I see you fail to recognize me because my appearance has changed.
&lrm;看來我換了容貌，邸下沒認出來
It is me.
&lrm;是我啊
Your long-time master
&lrm;邸下多年來的師父
and Gwanju of Cheonbugwan,
&lrm;天府館館主
Jin Mu.
&lrm;陳武
Jin Mu?
&lrm;陳武？
How can you be Jin Mu?
&lrm;你怎會是陳武？
I shifted into another body when I was in Gwido.
&lrm;我在鬼島取得他人之軀，因而生還了
You shifted your soul?
&lrm;你還魂了？
His Majesty sent someone for me, so I was able to live.
&lrm;多虧殿下派人來救我 &lrm;我才得以活著回來
His Majesty saved you?
&lrm;殿下救了你？
I came back to help the King and the Unanimous Assembly
&lrm;我的回歸正是為了實現王
achieve their goal.
&lrm;與萬長會所願
Shut your mouth!
&lrm;住口！
His Majesty would never see eye to eye with you.
&lrm;殿下豈會與你連成一氣？
Jin Mu is telling the truth.
&lrm;陳武說得沒錯
Jin Mu will be standing with me and the Unanimous Assembly.
&lrm;陳武將與我和萬長會聯手
Your Majesty.
&lrm;殿下
Jin Mu, did you say you wish to take away
&lrm;陳武，你說想收回
the Crown Prince's Gold Plaque?
&lrm;世子的金牌是吧？
Yes, Your Majesty.
&lrm;是的
His Royal Highness stabbed me in the back,
&lrm;邸下捅了我一刀
so I should return the favor.
&lrm;我自然也該以牙還牙
I shall take away the Crown Prince's Gold Plaque.
&lrm;我要收回世子的金牌
You are no longer the heir to the throne.
&lrm;今後你不再是我王位的繼承人
Keep him locked up in here until I say otherwise.
&lrm;將世子囚禁於此 &lrm;直到我解除禁令為止
Yes, Your Majesty.
&lrm;是
Your Majesty, you are being fooled by him.
&lrm;殿下，您被他誆騙了
Your Majesty!
&lrm;殿下！
Jin Mu.
&lrm;陳武
What are you trying to do by fooling the King and Unanimous Assembly?
&lrm;你欺騙王與萬長會，究竟有何打算？
I am merely picking up where I left off.
&lrm;當然是繼續未完成之事
I shall head to Jinyowon and bring out the fire bird.
&lrm;我這就要去辰曜院取出火鳥了
Is Young Lady Bu-yeon
&lrm;復妍小姐此時
also not here?
&lrm;是否也不在府上？
Is she with Young Master Jang?
&lrm;她是否與我家少爺在一起？
Lady Jin.
&lrm;陳院長
What is going on between them?
&lrm;他們之間究竟是怎麼一回事？
I cannot tell you anything right now.
&lrm;我現在什麼都沒辦法告訴妳
Time will solve everything,
&lrm;但過段時間，事情便會迎刃而解
so please have patience and wait.
&lrm;還請妳先耐心等待
Does that mean you know where they are?
&lrm;這麼說，妳知道他們在哪對吧？
Maidservant Kim.
&lrm;金道主
My mother still has not fully recovered
&lrm;先前家母為徐律少爺的事耗盡氣力
after helping Young Master Seo.
&lrm;至今尚未恢復元氣
She needs to rest, so please go back home.
&lrm;她還需要多休養，妳先請回吧
Lady Jin, the mages of the Unanimous Assembly are here.
&lrm;院長，萬長會的眾術士闖進來了
What?
&lrm;什麼？
What do you think you are doing?
&lrm;你們這是在做什麼？
How dare you attempt to enter Jinyowon without my permission!
&lrm;竟敢未經同意 &lrm;就擅自闖到辰曜院門口？
Apologies, Lady Jin.
&lrm;陳院長，得罪了
We need to take out the artifact that is needed for the lake's rite.
&lrm;我們萬長會必須取出 &lrm;將用於敬天大祭的法器
Open the door to Jinyowon.
&lrm;將辰曜院的門打開吧
You came barging in here at this late hour to get the artifact
&lrm;你們竟只為了拿取祭典法器
for the lake's rite?
&lrm;大半夜闖入此處？
The royal family has approved it,
&lrm;此事已獲王室准許
so all you need to do is open that door.
&lrm;妳只要將這道門打開即可
I cannot do that.
&lrm;不可能
I cannot open that door even if the royal family orders it.
&lrm;即便是王室之命 &lrm;我也不能隨便打開這道門
Have you forgotten about the Jinyowon Plaque?
&lrm;諸位難道忘記陳家有一塊傍牌了嗎？
All the mages of the Unanimous Assembly are here except for Songrim,
&lrm;那麼眼下除了松林以外 &lrm;萬長會術士都已聚集在此
so we shall confiscate the plaque.
&lrm;我們就在此收回傍牌吧
Give us the plaque.
&lrm;將傍牌交出來
This is ridiculous.
&lrm;豈有此理？
I cannot let you do that.
&lrm;我絕不允許你們這麼做
Enough!
&lrm;夠了！
I told you we have no time.
&lrm;都跟你們說沒時間了
-Mother! -Make one more step and your mother dies.
&lrm;-娘！ &lrm;-再靠近一步，妳娘必死無疑
Ho-gyeong.
&lrm;姐
Your brother has shifted souls.
&lrm;弟弟還魂了
Open that door before I suck out all the energy of the Jin family
&lrm;在我吸乾妳最引以為傲的 &lrm;陳家元氣之前
that you are so proud of.
&lrm;乖乖打開那道門吧
Jin Cho-yeon!
&lrm;陳超妍！
Open that door.
&lrm;把那道門打開
Or I will drain your mother's energy until she is as dry as firewood.
&lrm;否則我將吸乾妳娘的水氣 &lrm;讓她變成一具乾屍
Mother…
&lrm;娘
Open the door.
&lrm;把門打開
Do it now!
&lrm;快！
He is a soul shifter.
&lrm;他是還魂人
If he drains Lady Jin's energy, she will die!
&lrm;要是被吸乾水氣，陳院長必死無疑！
Hurry and open the door!
&lrm;快將門打開！
Quickly go to Songrim and ask them for help.
&lrm;妳快到松林搬救兵
Hurry.
&lrm;快去
Mother!
&lrm;娘！
Mother, are you all right?
&lrm;娘
Is that the fire bird's egg?
&lrm;這就是火鳥蛋嗎？
-What is that sound? -What is that?
&lrm;-這是什麼聲音？ &lrm;-怎麼回事？
Jinyowon must be collapsing now that the fire bird's egg is out.
&lrm;看來是火鳥蛋被取出 &lrm;辰曜院要坍塌了
We must leave now.
&lrm;我們快離開這裡！
Ho-gyeong.
&lrm;姐
I could have absorbed all your energy, but I could not bear to.
&lrm;我雖能吸取妳的元氣，但我辦不到
Anything that belongs to Jinyowon makes me sick to my stomach.
&lrm;因為辰曜院的一切 &lrm;我光想都覺得噁心
Mother.
&lrm;娘
Your wound is deep.
&lrm;妳的傷勢太重了
We cannot let them take the fire bird.
&lrm;火鳥不能被他們搶走
Go to Songrim right now and ask them for help.
&lrm;妳立刻去找松林的人幫忙
Jin Cho-yeon! Go now!
&lrm;陳超妍，快去！
Hurry!
&lrm;快！
Yes, Mother.
&lrm;好
Jinyowon…
&lrm;辰曜院
is collapsing.
&lrm;正在坍塌
No.
&lrm;不行
No…
&lrm;不可以
Lady Jin.
&lrm;陳院長
Lady Jin, are you all right?
&lrm;院長，妳還好嗎？
Please take me inside Jinyowon.
&lrm;妳快把我帶進辰曜院
If Jinyowon collapses,
&lrm;辰曜院若是塌了
all the relics inside will escape.
&lrm;裡頭的妖器就會通通竄逃而出
I must use my divine powers to keep them there.
&lrm;我必須用我的神力困住它們
Hold onto me.
&lrm;那妳靠著我
I will take you inside.
&lrm;我扶妳進去
My lord.
&lrm;首領
-Young Master Park. -Are you all right?
&lrm;-少爺 &lrm;-妳沒事吧？
The mages of the Unanimous Assembly took the fire bird.
&lrm;萬長會的術士們取走了火鳥
Jinyowon is going to collapse.
&lrm;辰曜院就快坍塌了
I will check on Jinyowon.
&lrm;我去看看辰曜院的情況
Go and follow the mages who took the fire bird.
&lrm;你去追那些取走火鳥的術士
-Yes, my lord. -The fire bird is a dangerous relic,
&lrm;-是 &lrm;-火鳥是危險的妖器
so I shall go with Young Master Park.
&lrm;我跟當具少爺一起走
My mother is severely injured.
&lrm;家母傷勢嚴重
Please help her, Lord Park.
&lrm;一切就拜託你了，首領
All right.
&lrm;好
Uncle.
&lrm;叔父
Where is Lady Jin?
&lrm;陳院長在哪？
She went inside to keep the relics from escaping.
&lrm;聽聞她為了守住妖器，進到裡頭了
Maidservant Kim went in there with her.
&lrm;是金道主扶著她一起進去的
Maidservant Kim?
&lrm;金道主？
Maidservant Kim is inside Jinyowon?
&lrm;金道主在辰曜院裡？
Maidservant Kim!
&lrm;金道主！
Maidservant Kim, are you in there?
&lrm;金道主！妳在裡面嗎？
Lord Park, I am in here!
&lrm;首領，我在這裡！
The relics are escaping!
&lrm;妖器開始逃竄了！
If it collapses,
&lrm;辰曜院若就這麼坍塌
all the other dangerous relics will escape as well!
&lrm;裡面那些危險的妖器會全數竄逃而出
I must seal the door.
&lrm;我必須把門關上
Maidservant Kim, hurry up and leave.
&lrm;金道主，妳快出去吧
If you do not, you will die.
&lrm;否則妳會沒命
What?
&lrm;什麼？
The relics are starting to escape.
&lrm;這裡的妖器要逃到外界了
I must seal the door!
&lrm;我必須趕快將門關上！
What about you?
&lrm;那妳呢？
Maidservant Kim!
&lrm;金道主！
It is going to collapse soon!
&lrm;辰曜院就快塌了！
If we do not seal the door, we will not be able to stop the relics!
&lrm;再不關門就攔不住那些妖器了！
No!
&lrm;不可以！
I cannot seal the door. Maidservant Kim is still…
&lrm;我不能關門，金道主還在…
My wife is still in there.
&lrm;我妻子還在裡面
My lord!
&lrm;首領！
Seal…
&lrm;把門
the door.
&lrm;關上吧
Maidservant Kim!
&lrm;金道主！
We cannot let this place collapse.
&lrm;這裡若是坍塌就糟了
So please…
&lrm;所以
seal the door.
&lrm;你把門關上吧
I understand.
&lrm;我都明白的
My lord.
&lrm;首領
I will be all right.
&lrm;我不要緊
So seal the door.
&lrm;所以你快關門吧
Hurry!
&lrm;快啊！
My lord! It is about to collapse!
&lrm;首領，辰曜院真的要塌了！
Even if you decide to seal that door,
&lrm;即便你真的決定關上那道門
I know how heartbreaking it will be for you,
&lrm;我也明白你有多麼痛徹心腑
so it does not upset me so much.
&lrm;所以我不會太難過
I do not mind it.
&lrm;我戴在這裡也無妨
Yeon…
&lrm;阿燕
Lord Park Jin.
&lrm;朴進首領
Do not fall into despair.
&lrm;你不必太絕望
You still have a chance to save her.
&lrm;你還有機會救她
I will give you the power to save the person you love.
&lrm;我可以給你拯救心愛之人的力量
Your Majesty…
&lrm;殿下
is this what you
&lrm;您與萬長會
and the Unanimous Assembly both want?
&lrm;已經連成一氣了嗎？
I told you.
&lrm;我說過了
Everyone wants to share the power of the ice stone.
&lrm;冰石之力人人都想要
It would be greedy of Songrim to keep it for themselves.
&lrm;僅由松林獨占，那就太貪心了
The power should be divided among the powerful mage families of Daeho
&lrm;冰石之力應由大湖國 &lrm;力量最高強的幾大術士家族平分
and used wisely through common consent.
&lrm;並在經過商議後，好好運用那股力量
So you plan to awaken
&lrm;為了得到冰石
the dangerous fire bird just to achieve that?
&lrm;你們竟要將危險的火鳥放出世間？
The lake's rite will bring us rain
&lrm;只要我們舉行敬天大祭成功祈雨
and help us get the ice stone.
&lrm;同時獲得冰石
Then we will seal it back.
&lrm;便可再將火鳥封印
What about the world that will burn to ashes because of it?
&lrm;那麼即使世間因此
Does that not matter to you?
&lrm;你們也不在乎嗎？
All things require sacrifice.
&lrm;凡事皆是有捨才有得
Worrying about insignificant things
&lrm;若一點犧牲都捨不得
only prevents us from achieving what we want.
&lrm;便達不到真正的目的
Do you not wish
&lrm;你還得救金道主呢
to save Maidservant Kim?
&lrm;你難道不想救她嗎？
Do not be a hypocrite and pretend that is not what you want.
&lrm;你就別口是心非，擺出偽善模樣了
Evil…
&lrm;惡人…
always does what it wants without ever stopping.
&lrm;如此肆無忌憚地為非作歹
But why is it that virtue
&lrm;善者為何
always needs to prove itself over and over again?
&lrm;非得一次次地證明自己？
Yes.
&lrm;是
I do wish to save her.
&lrm;我想救她
I would do anything to save her, even if it meant
&lrm;我多想放下理智，不計一切代價
I would lose my sanity.
&lrm;去救她
But even so,
&lrm;但即使如此
I will…
&lrm;我…
stop you from getting what you want.
&lrm;依然要阻止你們的作為
Not a single one of you
&lrm;你們這些人
has the right to laugh at me…
&lrm;沒有資格嘲諷…
and call me…
&lrm;我這股意志是…
a hypocrite.
&lrm;偽善
Stop right now…
&lrm;你再不住手…
or I will break the barrier of the fire bird.
&lrm;我便直接在此打破火鳥的結界
This place is going to burn down.
&lrm;這裡即將被烈火籠罩
We need to leave.
&lrm;大家快走吧
He fought against the representatives of eight families
&lrm;一人對抗八大家族的宗主
and still made it this far.
&lrm;還能撐這麼久
He really was a highly skilled mage.
&lrm;果然是個法術高強的首領
What a waste.
&lrm;真是可惜了
If he held hands with us, I would have helped him shift souls.
&lrm;倘若他願與我們聯手 &lrm;我還能保他一命，讓他還魂
But he willingly chose death,
&lrm;既然他寧願一死
so there is nothing we can do.
&lrm;那也無可奈何了
Lord Park!
&lrm;首領！
-Lord Park!
&lrm;-首領！
-Lady Jin!
&lrm;-院長！
Lord Park!
&lrm;首領！
Uk.
&lrm;阿煜
Uk, Jin is…
&lrm;阿煜，阿進…
Jin is…
&lrm;阿進…
-Lady Jin! -Lord Park!
&lrm;-院長！ &lrm;-首領！
Last night,
&lrm;昨晚
the fire bird was taken from Jinyowon.
&lrm;辰曜院的火鳥已經被取出
Lady Jin and Maidservant Kim went inside Jinyowon
&lrm;當時為了防止妖器逃竄
in an attempt to stop the relics from escaping…
&lrm;陳院長和金道主進入辰曜院…
and passed away.
&lrm;後來葬身於內
Not even Jin Cho-yeon could open the collapsed door to Jinyowon
&lrm;就連陳超妍的能力 &lrm;也打不開辰曜院坍塌的門
so we could not collect their bodies.
&lrm;因此沒能為她們兩位收屍
Because of that…
&lrm;所以…
their coffins are empty.
&lrm;她們的棺木是空的
As for Lord Park, he tried to stop them from breaking the fire bird's barrier,
&lrm;另外，首領原本試圖 &lrm;阻止他們打破火鳥的結界
but the fire bird's energy set the place on fire,
&lrm;後來那裡因火鳥之力而起火
and he passed away there.
&lrm;首領命喪火窟
The place completely burned down.
&lrm;那裡也被燃燒殆盡
The only thing we found there was his sword.
&lrm;我們只找到首領遺留的劍
I was locked up after they took away my Gold Plaque.
&lrm;他們奪走我的金牌，將我囚禁
I narrowly escaped when the fire broke out.
&lrm;我好不容易才趁著火災逃出來
My father, the King of this country,
&lrm;我的父親，這一國之王
is with the Unanimous Assembly.
&lrm;也跟萬長會沆瀣一氣
This all happened
&lrm;這一切
because Jin Mu was able to shift his soul into Seo Yun-o's body.
&lrm;都是陳武還魂到徐潤娛身上 &lrm;惹出來的事
I would barge into Cheonbugwan right this instant,
&lrm;我真想立刻衝進天府館算帳
but they have the fire bird.
&lrm;但他們手上有火鳥
We cannot make rash decisions.
&lrm;我們不能輕舉妄動
If people find out that the fire bird got out,
&lrm;倘若世人知道火鳥已被取出
there will be extreme chaos.
&lrm;必定會造成極大的紛亂
Let us quietly hold their funerals.
&lrm;我們先悄悄為他們三位辦好後事
Then we must stop them from waking the fire bird.
&lrm;再來想辦法阻止他們喚醒火鳥
The fire bird will awaken.
&lrm;火鳥必定會甦醒
I was told that
&lrm;我已經
it is going to happen no matter what.
&lrm;得知此事終將發生
However…
&lrm;不過…
these three did not pass away.
&lrm;他們三位並沒有死
If the disaster created by human greed was foreseen,
&lrm;若已預知人性貪婪將帶來禍患
the will to stop it can become a variable…
&lrm;那麼欲挺身阻止之人的意志 &lrm;將成為變數…
and change the outcome.
&lrm;進而改變結局
Jin will be all right.
&lrm;阿進不會有事的
Do not cry too much.
&lrm;妳別哭得太傷心
All right.
&lrm;好
Lady Jin, you have used up too much of your energy.
&lrm;陳院長，妳也耗了過多氣力
Not only did they take the fire bird,
&lrm;我讓火鳥遭人搶奪
but I also failed to stop all the relics…
&lrm;就連辰曜院的妖器竄逃
from escaping Jinyowon.
&lrm;我也沒能全數阻攔
You put your life at risk and did your best.
&lrm;妳已豁出性命竭盡全力了
Was it Bu-yeon who entered Jinyowon…
&lrm;辰曜院坍塌後進去的人
while it was collapsing?
&lrm;是復妍嗎？
Yes.
&lrm;沒錯
Jinyowon's door was built by Jin Seol-ran as well.
&lrm;辰曜院的門也是陳雪蘭所設
Bu-yeon created a door that allowed her to enter Jinyowon from Danhyanggok.
&lrm;復妍在斷響谷造了一道 &lrm;能進入辰曜院的門
While she entered Jinyowon and stopped it from collapsing,
&lrm;在她進入辰曜院，阻止辰曜院坍塌時
I followed her instructions and went to find the fire bird.
&lrm;我按她所說，去了火鳥所在之處
I could not find the fire bird.
&lrm;我雖未找到火鳥
But fortunately, I was able to save Jin.
&lrm;但幸好尚能救回阿進
Does that mean Naksu no longer lives
&lrm;那麼落壽在那副身軀裡的靈魂
in that body?
&lrm;完全消失了嗎？
She left the body,
&lrm;因為她已離去
which led Bu-yeon to completely regain her divine powers.
&lrm;那副身軀的神力才能全然復原
It took you so long to find each other again.
&lrm;你們好不容易才找到彼此
But you were not even given a full day together.
&lrm;竟然連一天都不能好好在一起
The yin-and-yang jade
&lrm;陰陽玉
is shared by couples in order to stay together.
&lrm;一人一顆是為了讓兩個人在一起
So we can no longer…
&lrm;但我們…
be sharing this.
&lrm;可能無法再共有這對玉了
When I recall that last memory…
&lrm;等我想起最後的記憶
I will give you a sign like this.
&lrm;我會這樣給你信號
I guess we were…
&lrm;我們…
never fated to recognize each other at first sight.
&lrm;似乎注定不該一眼認出彼此
My birth led to your father's death.
&lrm;我的出世導致妳父親身亡
Then you killed me to avenge him.
&lrm;而妳因為報仇而殺了我
You are right.
&lrm;沒錯
Judging by the fate that we share…
&lrm;若照這樣的孽緣來看
we probably should not have met.
&lrm;我們確實不該相遇
But…
&lrm;但是…
fate was not what brought us…
&lrm;我們之所以一眼認出彼此
to recognize each other at first sight.
&lrm;不是因為命中註定
We…
&lrm;我們…
lightened up each other's lives when we needed each other the most.
&lrm;是在最渴望彼此的瞬間 &lrm;出現在對方人生中的一道光
We embraced the shadows that came with it…
&lrm;並擁抱著光帶來的影
and chose to love each other.
&lrm;選擇彼此相愛的
So now…
&lrm;所以…
there is only one reply I can give you
&lrm;在我們最後的時刻
in our last moment together.
&lrm;我能給你的答覆只有一個
I love you.
&lrm;我愛你
Songrim is mourning, and the fire bird is in our hands.
&lrm;松林正在治喪，加上火鳥在我們手中
Neither Jang Uk nor Songrim will be able to do anything now.
&lrm;張煜和松林都不可能輕舉妄動
Tonight, I will wake the fire bird and perform the lake's rite.
&lrm;今晚我便會喚醒火鳥，舉行敬天大祭
Then after tonight, I will be able to use the power of the ice stone
&lrm;那麼過了今天，我就能得到冰石
and finally abandon this weak, ill body.
&lrm;擺脫這副體弱多病的身軀了
People could show up to hinder our plan,
&lrm;進行敬天大祭之時，也許會有人搗亂
so please gather all the guards protecting Daeho Fortress
&lrm;還請殿下召集所有 &lrm;守衛大湖城的防衛軍
and have them protect Cheonbugwan.
&lrm;來駐守天府館
I will send my army to Cheonbugwan.
&lrm;我會將我的軍隊派到天府館
I want you to safely awaken the fire bird
&lrm;你務必平安喚醒火鳥
and bring me the ice stone.
&lrm;將冰石送到我手中
Your Royal Highness,
&lrm;邸下
please stop the King from mobilizing his army.
&lrm;請您阻止王調動軍隊
But I no longer have the Gold Plaque that gives me power over the army.
&lrm;但我手上已經沒有 &lrm;能夠調動軍隊的王室金牌了
Use this.
&lrm;用它吧
This was left for you by the late king.
&lrm;這不是先王留給你的嗎？
This country does not need a king
&lrm;現在這個國家需要的
who does not care whether or not the world burns to ashes.
&lrm;不是一個無視天下即將陷於火海的王
It needs a king who wishes to stop it.
&lrm;而是願意挺身阻止的王
I already stole your King's Star.
&lrm;先前我已盜用過你的帝王星
Now I will even be using your Gold Plaque.
&lrm;如今竟又要拿你的金牌來用
Jang Uk.
&lrm;張煜
Have you really never dreamed of becoming the most powerful person
&lrm;你當真從未想過要登上這世間的
in this world?
&lrm;至高之位嗎？
I have already climbed
&lrm;我已經和我許諾之人
to the very peak of this world with the person…
&lrm;一起登上我一直以來最想到達的
I made that promise with.
&lrm;至高之處了
That is…
&lrm;那對我而言…
more than enough for me.
&lrm;便已經足夠
While we perform the lake's rite,
&lrm;舉行敬天大祭之時
the King will send his army to Cheonbugwan and protect it.
&lrm;王會調派軍隊來守衛天府館
Jang Uk and Songrim might come to stop us.
&lrm;張煜和松林說不定會來阻止
What are you worried about? We have the fire bird.
&lrm;火鳥在我們手中，擔心什麼？
You saw Park Jin.
&lrm;你也看到朴進的下場了
He could not do anything despite his strength and power.
&lrm;他功力如此高強 &lrm;也束手無策，只能吃敗仗
I guess you are right. Once we break the fire bird's barrier,
&lrm;也對，只要我們打破火鳥的結界
Jang Uk and Songrim will become helpless.
&lrm;張煜和松林想必也無計可施
Awakening the fire bird is dangerous.
&lrm;喚醒火鳥十分危險
If the flames burst toward us while we break the barrier,
&lrm;稍有差池，火鳥的焰氣 &lrm;碰到我們這些打破結界的人
we will instantly be reduced to ashes.
&lrm;我們便可能剎時化為灰燼
If the fire bird fails to fly after being disturbed
&lrm;倘若喚醒火鳥時出了差錯 &lrm;導致牠沒能飛上天
and its energy of fire bursts…
&lrm;焰氣爆發的話
all of Daeho Fortress will burn.
&lrm;大湖城便會陷入一片火海
They will not be able to do anything…
&lrm;他們怕火鳥被喚醒…
fearing that the fire bird might awaken.
&lrm;肯定什麼都做不了
I am going to go to Cheonbugwan and awaken the fire bird.
&lrm;我會直接到天府館將火鳥喚醒
You are going to awaken the fire bird, not stop it from awakening?
&lrm;你不是要阻止 &lrm;而是要直接喚醒火鳥？
If the awakening of the fire bird is inevitable,
&lrm;如果無可避免
it is better to let it happen while we still have control over it
&lrm;那不如在我們 &lrm;還能控制的時候先發制人
so we can change the outcome.
&lrm;由我們來改變結果
At the place where the energy of the sky
&lrm;我要在蒼天氣息觸及大地
reached the ground and created a huge form of energy,
&lrm;形成巨大水氣之處
I will get rid of the fire bird that is filled with the energy of fire.
&lrm;困住滿是焰氣的火鳥，將牠消滅
In order to do that,
&lrm;為此
I must awaken the fire bird.
&lrm;我必須喚醒火鳥
I checked the energy of the sky through the constellation basin.
&lrm;我已至天府館宿星台看過天象
The energy of fire will be strongest between 7 and 9 p.m. tonight.
&lrm;今晚戌時火的能量最為旺盛
Once that time comes, I shall begin the lake's rite.
&lrm;戌時一到就立刻開始舉行敬天大祭
Cheonbugwan will begin performing the rite between 7 and 9 p.m. tonight.
&lrm;天府館傳來消息說戌時一到 &lrm;祭典便會立刻舉行
During that time?
&lrm;戌時？
Have the guards protecting Daeho Fortress headed to Cheonbugwan?
&lrm;守衛大湖城的防衛軍去天府館了嗎？
The leader of the guards will be here soon to give you a report.
&lrm;防衛軍隊長稍後 &lrm;便會來向殿下報告情況
Good.
&lrm;好
Is it not time yet?
&lrm;戌時還沒到嗎？
Why is the leader of the guards not here to report yet?
&lrm;防衛軍隊長為何還沒來向我報告？
The guards will not be going anywhere.
&lrm;防衛軍不會有任何行動
I…
&lrm;因為
withdrew the order you gave, Your Majesty.
&lrm;我已收回殿下的王命
What is that?
&lrm;那是什麼？
Is that not a Gold Plaque?
&lrm;那不是金牌嗎？
It is the Gold Plaque of the man you have feared all your life.
&lrm;這正是您此生最為畏懼的
The man born under the King's Star.
&lrm;伴隨帝王星出世之人的金牌
The King's Star?
&lrm;帝王星？
The man born under the King's Star
&lrm;擁有帝王星力量之人
will stop what is happening at Cheonbugwan.
&lrm;將會阻止天府館正在發生的事
Father.
&lrm;父王
It is time you step down from the throne…
&lrm;您是時候退下…
that kept you anxious all your life.
&lrm;那令您提心吊膽的王位了
What…
&lrm;這…
Relics that will ignite the fire bird's energy
&lrm;這些加劇火鳥焰氣的危險妖器
are placed all over the canal.
&lrm;遍布水路各處
We must find and destroy them all.
&lrm;我們必須全數搜出銷毀
-Let us hurry. -Yes, my lady.
&lrm;-動作要快 &lrm;-是
Songrim forces have entered Cheonbugwan.
&lrm;松林的人已經闖入天府館
It is not time yet, but let us begin.
&lrm;雖然戌時未到，但我們還是開始吧
It is dangerous to rush it.
&lrm;操之過急會有危險
If the energy of fire explodes, we will all die.
&lrm;萬一焰氣爆發，我們都會死
If we lose the fire bird, we will all be doomed.
&lrm;火鳥若是遭奪，我們一樣沒戲唱
That is better than burning to death.
&lrm;那也總好過被燒死
Count me out.
&lrm;我要退出
No one here has the right to stop this. Otherwise, you will die.
&lrm;現在誰都沒有退路 &lrm;一旦卻步，必死無疑
Now…
&lrm;來
I want all of you to wake the fire bird!
&lrm;通通一起將火鳥喚醒！
Jin Mu is right.
&lrm;陳武說得對
Let us wake the fire bird so we can get the ice stone.
&lrm;為了得到冰石
You were supposed to be careful. Why is it suddenly awakening?
&lrm;你說要小心點 &lrm;但牠為何突然甦醒了？
Jang Uk. What are you doing?
&lrm;張煜，你這是在做什麼？
I am helping you all awaken the fire bird.
&lrm;我在幫你們喚醒火鳥
Jang Uk, stop!
&lrm;快住手，張煜
If the energy of fire explodes, it will kill us all!
&lrm;萬一火鳥的焰氣爆發 &lrm;在場的我們通通會沒命！
Did you expect to live while the world went up in flames?
&lrm;你們認為世間陷入火海無妨
I am sorry, but I cannot allow that.
&lrm;很抱歉，我不容許那種事發生
Jang Uk.
&lrm;張煜
Do you plan to kill everyone in the Unanimous Assembly?
&lrm;難道你想殺了萬長會所有人？
Is this not the kind of world you wanted?
&lrm;這不就是你殷殷企盼的天下嗎？
Take a close look at what it is like for someone with strength
&lrm;你就睜大雙眼看清楚 &lrm;強者掌握更強的力量恣意操縱
to gain and wield even greater power.
&lrm;會是什麼樣子
Jang Uk.
&lrm;張煜
You were right, Jang Uk.
&lrm;你說得對
In a world where those with strength gain greater power,
&lrm;在強者掌握一切的世上
the weak will just perish.
&lrm;弱者只有滅亡一途
Jin Bu-yeon safely arrived at Cheonbugwan.
&lrm;陳復妍已經平安進入天府館
She and Yul are waiting for the fire bird by the constellation basin.
&lrm;她正和阿律在宿星台等待火鳥
All right.
&lrm;好
Take this to Jin Bu-yeon and tell her
&lrm;把這個交給陳復妍
that I will be waiting at Lake Gyeongcheondaeho.
&lrm;告訴她我會在敬天大湖等
I found Jang Uk's constellation plate where the Crown Prince said it would be.
&lrm;我在世子說的地方 &lrm;找到張煜的星宿盤了
Is the fire bird safe?
&lrm;火鳥還安好嗎？
Jin Bu-yeon has regained all of her divine powers.
&lrm;這是神力全然復原的陳復妍
And the fire bird is safe.
&lrm;火鳥沒事
She will awaken it atop the constellation basin.
&lrm;待會她將在宿星台上喚醒火鳥
We got rid of all the relics that would prevent the fire bird
&lrm;那些阻止火鳥前往敬天大湖的妖器
from going to Lake Gyeongcheondaeho.
&lrm;已經全數清除了
The star in the very center of the Big Dipper is the King's Star.
&lrm;位於北斗七星中央的那顆便是帝王星
Now she will wake the fire bird
&lrm;接下來她會喚醒火鳥
and send it to the King's Star.
&lrm;送牠去找帝王星
I heard that
&lrm;聽聞
the seven stars gather their energy and send it to the King's Star.
&lrm;要聚集七顆星的水氣才能傳給帝王星
But right now, there are only six of us.
&lrm;但我們這裡才六個人
No, there are seven.
&lrm;不，有七個人
There is one more person…
&lrm;還有一個人…
who was always beside Uk.
&lrm;一直在阿煜身邊
Now she will wake the fire bird
&lrm;接下來她會喚醒火鳥
and send it to Uk at Lake Gyeongcheondaeho.
&lrm;讓牠去敬天大湖找阿煜
-How beautiful. -What is that?
&lrm;-好漂亮 &lrm;-那是什麼啊？
-Do you know what that is?
&lrm;-那是什麼？ &lrm;-你們知道那是什麼嗎？
Look at that.
&lrm;快看那裡
The fire bird is awake.
&lrm;火鳥甦醒了
Jang Uk did it.
&lrm;張煜做到了
The fire bird
&lrm;火鳥
has disappeared.
&lrm;已經消失了
-Jin Bu-yeon. -Shaman.
&lrm;-陳復妍 &lrm;-女巫
Bu-yeon.
&lrm;姐姐
To the light that has saved the world,
&lrm;拯救世界的光
I shall now return your shadow.
&lrm;這是我要歸還給你的影子
A light that embraces a shadow
&lrm;擁抱影子的光芒
will never be lost in darkness.
&lrm;永遠不會陷於黑暗
1 YEAR LATER
&lrm;（一年後）
Peekaboo.
&lrm;唉呀
How lovely.
&lrm;好可愛
I cannot believe two of these precious babies came out at once.
&lrm;這麼可愛的寶貝竟然一次來了兩個
Peekaboo.
&lrm;“唉呀
How lovely.
&lrm;好可愛
-How lovely.
&lrm;-好可愛” &lrm;-好可愛
What are Dan and Gang doing here again?
&lrm;亶兒跟崗兒怎麼又在這裡？
Oh, dear.
&lrm;唉唷
There we go.
&lrm;來
Are you Gang or Dan?
&lrm;你是崗兒還是亶兒啊？
He came with his wife to leave them here to visit his mother-in-law.
&lrm;他們小倆口把孩子 &lrm;寄託在我這，就回娘家去了
They always ask you to babysit for them
&lrm;他們動不動就把孩子交給你顧
and go on dates.
&lrm;自己跑去玩樂
What about us?
&lrm;那我們怎麼辦？
We are newlyweds too.
&lrm;我們也是新婚夫妻啊
This is why we are never able to go on trips to places far away.
&lrm;他們這樣害我們 &lrm;都無法遠行去慶祝新婚
Stop babysitting for them.
&lrm;你別老是幫他們帶孩子
If you keep doing this, they will never stop asking.
&lrm;你要是看他們可愛就答應 &lrm;那會沒完沒了
What would you do if they were Uk's babies?
&lrm;如果他們是阿煜夫妻倆的孩子
-Would you still not babysit them? -Young Master Jang?
&lrm;-妳也會拒絕嗎？ &lrm;-我家阿煜少爺啊？
I can babysit 12 babies if it is for Young Master Jang.
&lrm;如果是阿煜少爺的孩子 &lrm;就算來一打，我都會幫忙顧
Your young master still comes first, right?
&lrm;妳果然還是把妳家少爺擺第一
He will forever be your number one.
&lrm;他大概永遠都是妳的第一順位
Goodness, do not be jealous.
&lrm;唉唷，你吃什麼醋？
What a relief.
&lrm;真是太好了
They are both handsome because they take after Young Lady Jin.
&lrm;兩個孩子都像超妍小姐，長得真俊俏
They have long arms and legs because they take after Dang-gu.
&lrm;他們像當具一樣手腳修長 &lrm;身形多好看
I know the babies are adorable but do not babysit them all the time.
&lrm;孩子們雖然可愛 &lrm;但你也別太常照顧他們
Only once in a while.
&lrm;偶爾就好
-Goodness. -What is the matter?
&lrm;-唉唷 &lrm;-怎麼了？
Maybe it is the honey biscuits I ate earlier.
&lrm;可能剛才吃的藥菓沒消化
Is it…
&lrm;嗯？
-Is it what I think it is? -No, it cannot be.
&lrm;-是不是… &lrm;-不是啦，不會的
Nothing is for sure yet.
&lrm;唉唷，還不確定啦
I have high expectations for you.
&lrm;我對你有很高的期望
Next time, I hope you have twin girls.
&lrm;下次一定要生對雙胞胎女孩
Does that mean you are disappointed that Gang and Dan are sons?
&lrm;難道崗兒和亶兒是男孩 &lrm;讓妳很失望嗎？
I am not disappointed, but they took their father's last name.
&lrm;我沒有失望，只是他們兩個姓朴啊
I am merely asking for a daughter who will carry on our family line.
&lrm;我是要你們生下可以繼承陳家的女兒
Uk told me not to dream of having a daughter
&lrm;不過阿煜跟我說生女兒
since they are planning to give birth to one.
&lrm;是他們夫妻的事，叫我別妄想
Did you say they are at North Fortress?
&lrm;他們倆現在是在北城嗎？
They caught one at North Fortress, then headed straight to Seoho Fortress.
&lrm;之前聽說他們在北城抓到一隻 &lrm;後來又去了西湖城
But I do not know when they will return.
&lrm;不曉得什麼時候會回來
They promised to return to celebrate the twins' 100th day.
&lrm;他們說孩子們百日宴時會回京城
Right.
&lrm;對了
Bu-yeon agreed to help out at Jeongjingak, so they might return sooner than planned.
&lrm;大姨子答應幫忙精進閣的事務 &lrm;他們說不定會更早回來
What do you mean, Bu-yeon agreed to help out at Jeongjingak?
&lrm;復妍要幫忙精進閣的事務？
Jeongjingak is recruiting new mages,
&lrm;精進閣要招募新的術士
and she promised Yul to interview them.
&lrm;她答應阿律要幫忙面試新人
Jeongjingak is recruiting mages through interviews?
&lrm;精進閣要透過面試招募新術士？
Seo Yul is now in charge of Jeongjingak,
&lrm;徐經大師創立的精進閣
which was established by Master Seo Gyeong.
&lrm;已經確定由徐律接管
He made that decision as the new leader of Jeongjingak.
&lrm;這是他身為精進閣新任閣主的決定
QUALIFICATIONS ANYONE WITH PASSION AND DETERMINATION
&lrm;（資格要求 &lrm;具熱誠與決心之男女老幼皆可）
Is this really how you plan to recruit new mages for Jeongjingak?
&lrm;你確定要用這種方式 &lrm;招募精進閣術士？
Then all sorts of people will apply.
&lrm;這樣阿貓阿狗都會來報名吧
Word has spread that Seo Yul is in charge of gathering pupils at Jeongjingak.
&lrm;徐律接管精進閣後 &lrm;要招募徒弟的消息一出
All the mages' children in the capital are very excited about it.
&lrm;全京城術士家族的子弟都滿心期待
However, if we recruit them this way, children from prestigious families
&lrm;不過用這種方式招募 &lrm;那些赫赫有名的家族
will most likely not apply out of pride.
&lrm;應該會因為拉不下臉而不報名
When Master Seo Gyeong built Jeongjingak, he would have wanted more
&lrm;我相信徐經大師當初創立精進閣
than for us to train children from prestigious families.
&lrm;定不只是為了聚集名門子弟 &lrm;讓他們修煉
But not everyone has the power to cast spells.
&lrm;不過法術可不是人人都能修煉的
I am not recruiting just anyone.
&lrm;我並非來者不拒
I will pick people with good energy and potential.
&lrm;我會挑選具備良好氣息與資質的人
And based on that, those two were the ones that you picked?
&lrm;所以他們就是你先挑出來的人選嗎？
The most powerful priestess in Daeho saw their energy and recommended them.
&lrm;他們是大湖國最厲害的神女 &lrm;看過氣息後所推薦的人
She even told me that if Sun-i is trained well,
&lrm;她還說純伊只要嚴加訓練
she could even outshine her own husband, Jang Uk.
&lrm;甚至可能成為超越她夫婿張煜的術士
She has the potential to outshine Jang Uk?
&lrm;能超越張煜的人才？
They are my first pupils.
&lrm;他們是我的第一批徒弟
I will train them rigorously and make sure they outperform Uk.
&lrm;我必定會嚴格訓練，讓他們超越阿煜
Seo Yul has always been fixated on being the best,
&lrm;徐律往日在精進閣修煉時
even when he used to train at Jeongjingak.
&lrm;也有十分執著的好勝心
Those two are going to have it tough thanks to their persistent master.
&lrm;他們兩個遇到這麼一個嚴師 &lrm;看來有苦頭吃了
Anyway, what matters is that Jin Bu-yeon vouched for them.
&lrm;不過他們既然是陳復妍擔保的人
So they must have something special.
&lrm;想必有些過人之處
I heard that she also secretly takes part
&lrm;據我所知，揀擇殿下的王妃時
in interviewing potential wives for His Majesty the King.
&lrm;她似乎也會幫忙私下觀相
She interviews them?
&lrm;觀相？
Master Heo.
&lrm;許大夫
Why are you staring at Young Lady Heo?
&lrm;你為何一直盯著小姐看？
I am trying to see if she is fit to be a queen.
&lrm;我在看我孫女是否有王妃相
A queen?
&lrm;王妃？
A long time ago, I gave Jang Uk my torrent of energy,
&lrm;以前我將真氣渡給張煜時
and he promised to grant me a wish in return.
&lrm;他承諾過有朝一日 &lrm;無論我有什麼要求，他都會答應
Married couples are one both in body and spirit,
&lrm;夫妻是一體的
so if the wife takes part in choosing the queen,
&lrm;既然他妻子會幫忙進行揀擇
I can ask them to pick my granddaughter.
&lrm;那我當然可以要他們挑選我孫女
But Master Heo. Young Lady Heo is currently seeing someone.
&lrm;可是許大夫，小姐最近有對象了
What?
&lrm;什麼？
Who?
&lrm;誰？
A young man once came with a broken arm.
&lrm;是之前一名手臂受傷前來求醫的青年
Since then, he brings flowers for her every time he visits.
&lrm;此後他每次來都會買花送小姐
Is that so?
&lrm;是嗎？
-What kind of man is he? -He is handsome.
&lrm;-他是什麼樣的人？ &lrm;-長得很俊俏
He is as handsome as Young Master Seo.
&lrm;與徐律少爺不相上下
Really?
&lrm;真的嗎？
I had no idea Yun-ok was seeing someone.
&lrm;沒想到贇鈺竟然有對象了
I am so proud of her.
&lrm;真懂事
Then instead of asking her to pick my granddaughter as queen,
&lrm;那我就不管什麼王妃揀擇了
I shall ask her to interview that man.
&lrm;我得先叫她幫我看看那個男的
Picking a wife for His Majesty is more urgent.
&lrm;殿下的王妃揀擇也迫在眉睫
He focuses only on taking care of political affairs,
&lrm;由於殿下過度忙於政事
and he frequently invites Master Lee to the palace.
&lrm;又經常召見李先生
Rumors say that His Majesty
&lrm;導致懷疑殿下
even may have appointed Master Lee as his master.
&lrm;拜李先生為師的風聞傳得沸沸揚揚
What?
&lrm;嗯？
Does that mean he is practicing chastity?
&lrm;這麼說，他斷根了？
They say the King of Daeho has cut off his libido.
&lrm;聽說大湖國的王斷根了
But then what about his successor?
&lrm;那他要如何誕下子嗣？
Did you not hear the rumor?
&lrm;你沒聽說嗎？
Rumor has it that the king before the last had a son.
&lrm;前兩任的先王還有個兒子
Yes, they say that his son is Jang Uk.
&lrm;喔，據傳那個兒子就是張煜
No wonder Jang Uk was always so extraordinary.
&lrm;怪不得張煜如此與眾不同 &lrm;原來都是有原因的
The moment I saw him beat the Crown Prince in a fight,
&lrm;以前張煜打贏世子的時候
I knew there was something special about him.
&lrm;我就料到他身世不凡了
Should I also try practicing chastity?
&lrm;我要不要也來試試斷根修煉？
Cut the nonsense.
&lrm;別傻了
Those men are unbelievable.
&lrm;這些男人就會出一張嘴
His Majesty should quickly get married
&lrm;王可要趕緊成婚
so that people stop saying he cut off his libido.
&lrm;才能消弭這些斷根的風言風語
I cannot believe people think that I, the King, cut off my libido.
&lrm;我這個一國之王斷根？
That is surely
&lrm;以前
the most absurd thing I have heard since a bogus shaman told me
&lrm;有個荒唐女巫叫我把烏龜當子孫養
to adopt a turtle as my son.
&lrm;這是繼她之後最荒謬的話
-I am the King. -Exactly.
&lrm;-我可是王 &lrm;-所以
That is why you should quickly find yourself a wife.
&lrm;殿下才更應該早日覓得王妃啊
But Jin Bu-yeon promised
&lrm;陳復妍明明說回來後
to come back and send royal notices to the women she already picked out.
&lrm;會把她提前看過氣息的 &lrm;閨女八字帖送過來
When will those two be back?
&lrm;他們兩個到底何時才要回來？
What they are doing is also important, and they still seem pretty busy.
&lrm;他們夫妻倆也是身負重任 &lrm;想必忙得不可開交
How many relics escaped Jinyowon when it collapsed?
&lrm;之前說辰曜院坍塌時 &lrm;有多少妖器竄逃出去？
A total of 31 escaped,
&lrm;總共有31件
and they have captured 12 as of now.
&lrm;目前已經收回12件
Among those, there is a mouse that goes around in human form,
&lrm;其中包含會幻化成人形的鼠妖
and a dangerous pipe that lures children.
&lrm;也有專挑幼童迷惑的危險笛子
Amid them, a crock that spreads rumors and causes strife,
&lrm;而善於挑撥離間的甕
and a crying frog that spreads plagues are especially dangerous.
&lrm;及會傳染瘟疫的哭泣之蛙尤為危險
They will have to stay busy in order to catch them all.
&lrm;要收回這麼多妖器，他們應該忙翻了
Jang Uk will likely use that
&lrm;有了這個藉口
as an excuse to reject my every offer to make him the Gwanju of Cheonbugwan.
&lrm;無論我如何央求 &lrm;張煜肯定不會接下天府館館主之位
I will suggest it once again the next time I meet him.
&lrm;待我下次見到他，我會再勸勸他
I will tell him to drop by the palace
&lrm;我會轉告他，殿下很想念他
since Your Majesty misses him dearly.
&lrm;讓他務必進宮一趟
This is the pottery that holds Gwiseo.
&lrm;這是裝鬼鼠的陶器
Tell them to capture the mouse and put it in here.
&lrm;麻煩轉告他們 &lrm;將逃走的鬼鼠抓進這裡收好
All right.
&lrm;好
I am relieved that you stopped many relics from escaping.
&lrm;當時真是多虧了妳 &lrm;才沒有讓全數妖器竄逃而出
If the swarm of mosquitoes that causes earthquakes had escaped,
&lrm;倘若引發地動的蚊群脫逃
it would have been very dangerous.
&lrm;那就真的危險了
I was able to live that day thanks to her.
&lrm;當時也是多虧那孩子 &lrm;我才能保住一命
Do you
&lrm;如今
no longer feel agony whenever you see her?
&lrm;妳見到她，心中不再難受了嗎？
Like you said,
&lrm;若如你所說
if it was really Jin Seol-ran's soul that was born through Bu-yeon's body,
&lrm;起初就是陳雪蘭的靈魂 &lrm;藉著復妍的肉身出世
and she chose that girl to protect that body
&lrm;既然她離開時選擇那孩子
as she left this world,
&lrm;來守住那副身軀
I choose to believe that my daughter is living on thanks to her.
&lrm;我就決定當作多虧有她在 &lrm;我女兒才得以活下去
This mouse eats the clippings of someone who trims their nails at night
&lrm;這隻老鼠會吃下 &lrm;人們晚上剪下丟棄的手腳指甲
and takes the appearance of that person.
&lrm;並幻化為那人的樣子
It transforms to look just like you, then goes to your house
&lrm;牠會化成你的樣子，假扮成你回家
and eats your parents alive!
&lrm;把你爹娘吃掉！
So…
&lrm;所以
always be careful where you throw away your nail clippings.
&lrm;你們剪下的手腳指甲 &lrm;千萬不能隨意丟棄
If you are scared, you can go and pray to the tree at Danhyanggok.
&lrm;你們如果害怕 &lrm;可以去求斷響谷的大樹保佑
There is a gigantic tree in Danhyanggok,
&lrm;斷響谷有一棵很高大的樹
and when there is a full moon, two people appear on top of that tree.
&lrm;聽說月圓之夜 &lrm;會有兩個人出現在樹頂上
They saved my big sister when she was being chased by a tiger.
&lrm;我姐姐被老虎追趕時 &lrm;就是他們出手相救的
They also summoned fireflies and lit up the dark path for her.
&lrm;他們還喚來螢火蟲，為她照亮夜路
-Really? -Is that true?
&lrm;-真的嗎？ &lrm;-你說的是真的嗎？
Do they show up there often?
&lrm;他們
Yes, I heard the man is very tall and the woman is very beautiful.
&lrm;對，聽說是一個很高的哥哥 &lrm;和一個很漂亮的姐姐
They are a married couple.
&lrm;他們是一對夫妻
He is a bright light that protects the world,
&lrm;他們一個是拯救天下的光芒
and she is a shadow that protects him by embracing the darkness surrounding him.
&lrm;一個是在光芒周遭的黑暗中 &lrm;守護他的影子
Darling.
&lrm;娘子
How long are you going to make me carry you up here?
&lrm;妳要讓我帶妳上來到什麼時候？
For eternity.
&lrm;一輩子
-For eternity? -You promised.
&lrm;-一輩子？ &lrm;-你答應我的啊
Right.
&lrm;嗯
What is the matter? Are you already tired of doing it?
&lrm;怎麼樣？夫君 &lrm;你已經開始嫌煩了嗎？
-No, of course not. -Forget it. Let us go down.
&lrm;-沒有，我… &lrm;-算了，我要下去了
No, wait.
&lrm;不是，等等…
It is not that I am tired of doing it.
&lrm;不是啦，我沒有嫌煩
You were once a mage who mastered Chisu.
&lrm;妳也曾是練就治水境界的術士
So I am merely telling you to challenge yourself.
&lrm;我的意思是妳可以自我挑戰一下啊
There is no need, for I possess divine powers.
&lrm;不必，我已經有高強的神力了
You want me to train again?
&lrm;要我重新開始修煉？
No way. Never. I get sick just thinking about it.
&lrm;我才不要，辦不到 &lrm;我光用想的就受不了
Gosh, back when you were my master,
&lrm;天啊，以前那個天天罵我懶惰
did you not always scold me for being lazy?
&lrm;老是把我往死裡逼的師父去哪了？
You were able to come this far thanks to your great master.
&lrm;你就是遇到如此優秀的師父 &lrm;才能有今天的成就
-What? -Be grateful and treat her well.
&lrm;-什麼？ &lrm;-以後務必心存感激，好好待她
All right, fine.
&lrm;是
So did you find the creature you were looking for?
&lrm;所以妳要找的傢伙找到了嗎？
-Did you see it? -Yes.
&lrm;-有看到牠嗎？ &lrm;-嗯
I saw it.
&lrm;看到了
It is in the west of the forest.
&lrm;在樹林西邊
It is a cat, a wily beast that escaped from Jinyowon.
&lrm;牠是從辰曜院脫逃的貓妖
A cat?
&lrm;貓啊？
Hey, I thought you said it was a cat?
&lrm;喂，妳不是說牠是貓嗎？
That growl sounds like it may be strong enough to eat a tiger.
&lrm;咆哮聲這麼驚天動地 &lrm;老虎都鬥不過牠吧
It is as big as an elephant.
&lrm;牠的體積
That is going to be
&lrm;看來會是一隻
one cute cat.
&lrm;可愛至極的貓啊
Stay close to me.
&lrm;靠緊我
Here it comes.
&lrm;牠來了
Go and take care of it.
&lrm;收了牠吧
Subtitle translation by: Joy Lee
&lrm;字幕翻譯：吳盈臻